# John Joseph Mazuch

315 Martin Street Folkston, GA 31537 (desire to relocate) **Phone:** (912)-276-1793 | **Email:** johnmazuch@gmail.com

I am a passionate, Full Stack Web Developer of two years and I love to code and design new projects. This includes testing and implementing changes with version control software, aiding in browser compatibility, responsive web design, and exercising my eye for detail to ensure proper quality of code and function. I am always eager to learn more and to work on a team to contribute to real-world projects.

### **DEVELOPER SKILLS**

Front-End	Back End	Source Control	Frameworks	Other
JavaScript ES6	MySQL	Git Bash	Bootstrap 3	MATLAB
CSS3 / LESS	Learning C# / ASP.NET	GitHub	Bootstrap 4	Visual Studio Code
HTML5	Node.js / JSON			HTTP Requests
jQuery	MongoDB and Robo 3T			Mongoose.js
Chart.js	Python			Testing with Mocha
	Express.js			Handlebars.js
	Postman			
		<b>PROJECTS</b>		

# Todo Project | Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, JSON, and Postman APIs

· Back-end programming with Node.js for a user to create a list of things to do and store in a database

Node Web Server | Node.js, Express.js, JSON, and Hosted On Heroku Built a web server to fetch geocode data using a Google API endpoint

# Bootstrap 4 Portfolio Site | Bootstrap - HTML5, CSS3, and Google Maps API

· First build using Bootstrap 4 to serve as my main page for displaying all of my work

### Content Slider | HTML 5, CSS3, jQuery

- · Built an image carousel for displaying images and features a forward and back button functionality Simple Quiz | HTML5, CSS3, jQuery
- · Quiz project which allows a user to fully interact and receive a score based on correct answers provided **Udacity Project - Detect Profanity | Python**
- · Constructed a program in Python to detect and alert of profanity in text documents along any file path Pixel Art Game - Grow With Google Scholarship | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery
- · Created a pixel game where a user could fully manipulate size of field, color, and create an illustration Authentication and Security | Node.js, MongoDB, JSON, Postman, Robo 3T, and Express.js
- · Utilized a web server and constructed a database to test user login authentication and functionality

## **EDUCATION**

### **Udacity - Grow With Google** January 2018 - April 2018 Front-End Web Developer Challenge Scholarship Recipient Georgia Southern University, Statesboro, GA August 2014 - August 2016 Completed Coursework in Mechanical Engineering Georgia Southern University, Statesboro, GA December 2013 Bachelor of Science in Psychology (graduated) Waycross College, Waycross, GA

May 2012

Associate of Science in Biological Sciences (graduated)

#### I.T. AND ENGINEERING RELATED SKILLS

- · Specialized in research methods
- · Front- and Back-End Web Development
- Server configuration and application deployment
- Data analysis and compilation
- · Analytical problem-solver and detail-oriented
- · Skilled at observing patterns and projections
- Utilize version control to enhance test security
- · Document and work to resolve all issues
- Perform various tests to ensure quality
- Anticipate company needs and plan accordingly
- · Quality assurance testing
- Documentation of software test results
- · Workflow optimization and multitasking
- Plan future software model configurations

### **INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

- Leadership and management skills
- · Strong verbal and written communication skills
- · Ability to work in a team and as a self-starter
- High level of accountability

- Creative and forward-thinking
- Active listening
- · Flexible and quick learning
- · Receptive of constructive criticism

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Bering Straits Logistics Services - Naval Submarine Base Kings Bay**

Security Clerk - SWFLANT Engineering Services Building

St. Marys, GA March 2019 - present

- · Perform all duties to the best of my ability with the highest level of integrity
- Maintain records and input data into computer filing system
- Implement various access control procedures toward visitors and personnel
- Exercise measures in preventing unauthorized building access
- Perform primary and secondary quality checks on handled documents
- Report any documentation discrepancies or security breaches to supervisors
- Retain Secret Security Clearance

# **Bering Straits Logistics Services - Naval Submarine Base Kings Bay**

St. Marys, GA September 2018 - *March 2019* 

Armed Security Officer

Certified on M500 Shotgun and Beretta M9 firearms

- Demonstrated awareness of all surroundings and remain vigilant
- Obtained Secret Security Clearance
- Exercised measures in preventing unauthorized base access

# The GEO Group - D. Ray James Correctional Facility

Folkston, GA

April 2017 - September 2018

Main Control Center Officer (Morning Watch)

· Monitored all security operations inside and outside of the facility

- · Coordinated and control emergency response with supervisors
- · Observed activities on facility cameras and report anomalous events
- · Maintained facility key and camera accountability and ensure proper functionality
- · Controlled access of facility staff to any and all areas of the facility upon verification
- Completed all necessary paperwork in a timely fashion

### Correctional Officer (Morning Watch)

- · Supervised inmates according to company policy under Federal BOP contract
- Provided counseling to inmates if and when necessary
- Ensured all inmates are in proper dress and on-time for various prison movements and count times
- · Monitored inmates in regards to their mental health and report moderate and serious signs of distress
- · Completed necessary fire and safety inspections and shakedowns
- · Confiscated any items which may pose a danger to the facility population and staff
- Used training in psychology to discern patterns of behavior and interact appropriately
- · Resolved conflicts in a fair, firm and consistent manner

### **Bella Terra: Interior Solutions**

CNC / Water Jet Operator

August 2016 - April 2017

- · Operated under contract with a large aerospace client
- Ensured desired tolerance is met with all surfaces to be cut on water jet
- · Employed routine quality assurance practices in all phases of machining
- Monitored machining progress for inconsistencies and correct accordingly
- Observed equipment safety protocols at all times of operation
- Tracked and update material inventory as necessary

### **Bella Terra: Interior Solutions**

Pooler, GA

Pooler, GA

Entry Level Maintenance Technician / Fabricator

August 2016 - April 2017

- · Upheld contractual agreement of non-disclosure of proprietary methods and trade secrets
- Serviced manufacturing machinery and ensure proper operation on a daily basis
- · Reported any malfunctions to head technician and troubleshoot accordingly
- · Performed routine inspections on all equipment in the facility and HVAC systems
- · Polished various high-value furnishing surfaces and verify readiness for further fabrication
- · Refinished wood work tables with the use of sanding tools and lightweight body filler
- Conducted research and development testing on a patent-pending invention
- · Anticipated the needs of personnel across all departments and planned maintenance strategically

**Foot Locker, Inc.**Waycross, GA
Sales Associate
November 2011 - August 2012

- Successfully formulated and applied short, persuasive product sales pitches
- · Consistently exceeded top sales performance quotas
- · Placed as number one Sales Associate in the district
- · Sold over \$40,000 of merchandise during period of employment

### STUDENT ORGANIZATION PARTICIPATION

# **Society of Manufacturing Engineers**

**Georgia Southern University** 

President

May 2016 - August 2016

- · Coordinated with Engineering Department faculty and staff
- · Worked with organization officers to develop and implement semester itinerary
- · Used concepts in entrepreneurship and management to shape outreach
- · Generated a need for student collaboration with the organization
- · Executed organization start-up operations for the Fall semester

### Society of Manufacturing Engineers

**Georgia Southern University** 

Vice President

August 2015 - May 2016

- · Coordinated with faculty and staff within the Engineering Department
- · Performed managerial tasks delegated by faculty, staff, and Chapter President
- · Established relations with companies and prospected for facility tours and speaker events
- · Collaborated with companies to coordinate and execute tour and event logistics
- · Independently developed strategic plans of action and presented to supervisors
- · Promoted the benefits of the university engineering facilities to student body
- · Worked various angles with chapter branding and marketing
- · Scheduled chapter meetings and prepared PowerPoint presentations accordingly
- Helped build the organization from the ground-up

### **American Society of Mechanical Engineers**

**Georgia Southern University** 

Professional Development Coordinator

October 2015 - May 2016

- · Exposed students to various academic opportunities for personal projects
- Used basic and advanced communication skills to deliver presentations
- · Employed motivational psychology to help improve student skill sets
- · Independently searched for opportunities to aid in student marketability
- · Assisted in résumé-building and resource accessibility

# References:

Dr. Dragoş Amarie - PhD Biophysics - Georgia Southern University - (812) 391 - 4415

Kyler L. Johnson - Senior Software Engineer - (912) 614 - 1266

Bella Terra: Interior Solutions, LLC Belinda Barfield - Vice President - (912) 965 - 9654 Robert Murphy - Design Engineering Supervisor - (912) 965 - 9654

The GEO Group / D. Ray James Correctional Facility Jerome DeForest - Captain - (912) 496 - 6242 Raymond Staines - Lieutenant - (912) - 816 - 2484